嘿  嘿  嘿  嘿
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
不准这样  还在我屋里  就得守规矩
None of that. Not while you're living under my roof.
什么
What?
就算我知道内幕  也不代表我喜欢看你们亲热
Look, just because I know about you two doesn't mean I like looking at it.
你试镜不是还有一小时才结束吗
Aren't you supposed to be at an audition for another hour?
很抱歉  我可不是中年黑人妇女
Well, I'm sorry if I'm not a middle-aged black woman.
而且还走错试镜场地
And I'm also sorry if sometimes I go to the wrong audition.
你们要我假装不知道  就得假装你们没怎样
Okay, look, if I have to pretend I don't know about you two,then you two are gonna have to pretend there's nothing to know about.
好  抱歉
Okay, sorry.
我听到了
I can hear that.
瑞秋还在上班
Rachel's at work.
我还是听得到
I can still hear you.
老友记  第五季  第06集  雪男
Friends  S05E06   The One With The Yeti
主演: 珍妮佛·安妮斯顿
主演: 寇妮·考克斯
主演: 丽莎·库卓
主演: 麦特·勒布兰
主演: 马修·派瑞
主演: 大卫·修蒙
嗨  嗨
Hey. Hey.
那是什么
Hey. What's that?
我妈寄给我外婆的祖传宝物
Yeah, my mom sent me a family heirloom that once belonged to my grandmother.
你们相信吗
Can you believe it?
一年前我连家人都没有  现在竟然有祖传家产
A year ago I didn't even have a family,and now I have heirlooms for crying out loud.
天啊
Oh, God!
好软
Oh, soft.
这是貂皮吗
Is this mink?
对  我妈为何寄皮草给我
Yeah! Why would my mother send me a fur?
她完全不了解我吗
Doesn't she know me but at all?
我已经有外套了  而且还没牺牲任何可怜动物
Plus, I have a perfectly fine coat that no innocent animals suffered to make.
只不过是时薪12分钱的九岁菲律宾童工
Yeah, just some 9-year-old Filipino kids who worked their fingers bloody...
卖命做的
...for 12 cents an hour.
别听我的  我胡说的
That didn't happen, I made that up.
嘿  罗斯
Hey. Ross?
罗斯  你不能在这里贴广告
Ross, you can't put up flyers in here.
为什么  别人都可以
How come? Everybody else does.
就是你不行
You can't.
什么东西
What is that?
我要处理掉一些家具
Oh, uh, I'm getting rid of a couple of things.
这是你所有家当
This is all of your things.
没错
Yes, yes, it is.
没关系  艾蜜莉说  我们应该买新家具
No, but it's good. Emily thinks we should get all new stuff.
光属于我们俩的家具  也都是全新的东西
Stuff that's just ours. Together, you know, brand new.
基本上这是 "瑞秋碰过的家具" 大拍卖
So basically this is a "getting rid of anything Rachel ever touched" sale.
摸过  用过  坐过  睡过的都不行
Touched, used, sat on, slept on...
我全买了
I'll take it all.
罗斯  你不反对
Hey, Ross, you're okay with that?
只要顺着艾蜜莉  她来纽约就没事了
Look, if I can just do what Emily wants,and get her to New York, I'm sure everything will be fine.
但是  这种做法也太极端了吧
Okay, but don't you think that's a little extreme?
毕竟是我说错名字  你能怪她吗
After what I did, can you blame her?
你已经算轻松了
Oh, my God. You got off easy.
我朋友席薇的老公在床上喊错名字  她就把他的小弟弟变绿了
When my friend Sylvie's husband said someone else's name in bed,she cursed him and turned his thingy green.
他这是做什么
What is he doing?
艾蜜莉觉得罗斯的家具  会沾上瑞秋的虱子吗
Emily thinks Ross' furniture has got Rachel cooties?
乔伊  别激动  不
Calm down, Joey. No.
我偏要  事情搞得乱七八糟
Everything's getting all messed up, you know?
艾蜜莉不准罗斯见瑞秋
Emily won't let Ross see Rachel.
可是我们会继续见瑞秋  因此罗斯再也不能见我们
We're not gonna stop seeing Rachel, hence, Ross stops seeing us.
我也不开心  一切都变了
Oh, I hate this. Everything's changing.
我知道  我们不能再见罗斯  乔伊还会用 "因此"
Yeah, I know. We're losing Ross, Joey said "hence."
我也不高兴
I'm not happy about this either,
但是  如果罗斯能开心
but, you know, if Ross says he's happy...
我们不该说出  自己对艾蜜莉的心情
...then we just have to keep our feelings about Emily to ourselves.
大家愿意吗
Are you cool with that?
不要
No.
不过我是演员
But, you know, I'm an actor.
我可以装得无所谓
I'll act cool.
天啊  我怕死储藏室了
Ooh. Oh, God, storage rooms give me the creeps.
摩妮卡  拜托  你快点
Monica, please, hurry up, honey, please.
瑞秋  你要吃小圆松饼  就得让我先找到煎盘
Rachel, if you want the little round waffles, you gotta have to wait until I find the little waffle iron.
我想吃小圆松饼  好吧
I want the little round waffles. All right.
找到了
Here it is.
就在杀虫药下面
Right underneath the can of bug bomb.
锅碗瓢盆怎么可以  放在毒药下面
I wonder if the best place to put something that cooks food is underneath the can of poison?
好吧  我吃土司好了
Okay, you know what? I'll have toast.
天啊  喷他喷他
Oh my God! Fog him! Fog him!
我不知道该如何处置这件皮草
I don't know what I'm gonna do about this coat.
可以给我
I'll take it.
好主意  太好了
That might work. Oh, yeah
真好  怎样  你们觉得如何
Huh? All right, what do you think?
五分钟后换你上台  明妮莉小姐
You're on in five, Ms. Minnelli.
不  只是有点突然
No, no, no, it's just a bit sudden.
其实我很高兴  也全力赞成
No, it's great, okay? I am totally on board.
我也爱你  好  再见
I love you too. All right, bye.
怎么了  罗斯
What's the matter, Ross?
没事  其实是件好消息
Nothing. Oh, actually, great news!
我刚跟艾蜜莉通过电话  看来我要搬家了
Um, just got off the phone with Emily,and looks like I'm moving to a new apartment.
为什么  她认为  而且我也同意
Why? Well, her thought is... And I agree.
既然要换新家具  干脆也换间公寓
Fresh new furniture, why not a fresh new apartment?
她表妹有个地方要分租
Her cousin has this great place to sublet.
一边可以看到河  一边可以看到哥伦比亚
It's got a view of the river on one side and Columbia on the other.
那是离市区很远的地方  大概要转搭三种车
That's way uptown. That's like three trains away...
太棒了
...which is great.
我喜欢搭火车
I love to ride that rail.
你真的同意
So you're really okay with this?
当然  离上班地点是有点远
Yes, yes. I mean, it's kind of far from work...
但是我通勤时就有很多时间
...but, uh, you know, I'll get so much done on the commute.
她算是送了我一份大礼  那就是时间
I've been given the gift of time.
真有意思  上次圣诞节  我还得到很多空间呢
That's so funny, because last Christmas I got the gift of space.
两样加起来就是有个小宇宙了
We should get them together and make a continuum.
现在还要搬家
Now he's moving?
艾蜜莉到底施了什么法啊
Man, what is Emily doing to him? Ow!
他又不在这里
He's not even here.
大家听我们说
You guys. You guys.
我们刚刚去储藏室  看到一个很可怕的人
We were just in the storage area and we saw this really creepy man.
目露凶光  全身毛茸茸
He was like this crazy-eyed, hairy beast-man.
就像大脚哈利或是喜马拉雅雪人
He was like a Bigfoot or a yeti or something.
而且他还拿着斧头  瑞秋只好拿杀虫药喷他
He came at us with an ax, so Rachel had to use the bug bomb on him.
我拉开拉环拼命喷他
Yeah, I pulled the tab and I just fogged his yeti ass.
深色头发  满脸胡须  对
Uh, like, dark hair, bushy beard? Yeah.
你们喷的是丹尼
Yeah, you fogged Danny.
拜托  才不是丹尼
Ugh, please. We did not fog Danny.
丹尼是谁
Who's Danny?
丹尼刚搬到楼下
Danny just moved in downstairs.
那家伙去安地斯山四个月  才刚回国  人很好
He just got back from this four-month trek in the Andes. Nice fella.
什么人很好  每次我们喷谁  你就帮他说话
Oh, he's nice. He's nice. You know, you always stick up for the people we fog.
什么事  嗨
Yeah? Hi.
你大概不记得  我们就是上次喷你的人
You might not remember us, but we are the girls that fogged you.
我们很抱歉  乱喷一通
We're really sorry we fogged you.
随便
Okay.
嗨  我们只是要告诉你  我们不是故意的
Hi, uh, just so you know, we didn't mean to fog you.
我们以为你是雪人还是怪物什么的
We actually thought you were like a yeti or something.
随便
Okay.
怎样
Yes?
嗨  抱歉打扰你
Hi. Ahem, sorry to bother you...
你接受我们道歉的态度  让我们很不爽
...but I don't think that we can accept your acceptance of our apology.
听起来一点也不真心
It just doesn't really seem like you mean it.
对
Yeah
随便
Okay.
那家伙真恶劣
Wow. That guy is so rude.
没错  他哪里有病
Really. What is with that guy?
换做我喷你  你早就原谅我了
I mean, you'd forgive me if I fogged you.
其实  你有喷到我  一点点
Well, you did, a little bit.
天啊  我很抱歉
Oh, my God, honey. I'm so sorry.
我完全不介意
I totally forgive you.
真的
Really?
嘿  嘿
Hey. Hey.
你知道  我那个开火葬场的朋友克里斯吧
So listen, you know my friend Chris who owns the crematorium?
火葬场那个克里斯  当然
Crematorium Chris? Sure.
他说他愿意免费帮我烧皮草
Well, he said that he would cremate my fur coat for free...
只要我介绍死人去他那里火化
...if I, um, you know, bring in the next person I know who dies.
天啊  好漂亮的皮草
Oh, my God.Oh, my God. Look at these pelts.
别太喜欢了  她要烧掉了
Don't get too attached. She's having it cremated.
什么
What...?
亲爱的菲比
Phoebe? Ha. Honey?
我知道你是个怪胎  大家平时也欣赏你这点
Honey, I know you're quirky, and I get a big kick out of it. We all do, actually.
但是你毁掉这么棒的皮草  实在是不合天理
But if you destroy a coat like this,I mean, that is like a crime against nature.
说错了  是有违时尚流行
Not nature. Fashion.
这叫做流行
This is fashion?
尸体叫做流行
Okay, so to you, death is fashion?
实在有意思
That's really funny.
接下来菲比为各位展示  最新的毛茸茸尸体
Here's Phoebe umm, sporting uh, y'know, cutting edge hairy carcass
这些动物死于寒冷的俄罗斯
...from, you know, the steel traps of wintry Russia.
你们真认为好看
I mean, you really think this looks good?
因为我觉得不赖
Because I do.
我也想念你  希望快点见到你
I know, I miss you too. I can't wait to see you.
我爱你  再见
I love you. Bye.
这什么  石头吗
Okay, what is in here, rocks?
不  我收集的化石样本
No, this is my collection of, uh, fossil samples.
就是石头嘛
So rocks.
我一定会想念这里
I'm really gonna miss this apartment. Heh.
小班就在那边学会走路的
You know, Ben took his first steps right over there.
记不记得我上次撞到这里  后来还昏倒了
Hey, remember when I ran into this thing and it kind of knocked me out a little?
我很喜欢这间公寓
I love this place.
老实说  我真希望别搬家
To tell you the truth, I wish I didn't have to move.
你的意思是你也不想走
Uh, are you saying that you're not entirely happy about this?
如果艾蜜莉给我选择的机会  你本来就有机会
Well, I mean, if, uh, Emily gave me a choice. You do have a choice.
罗斯  你为什么要听她的  你疯了吗
Ross, why are you listening to her? Are you crazy?
为什么
What?
艾蜜莉这些要求太过分
It's not right what Emily wants you to do
她根本就是
She is totally
不要再捏我了
Stop pinching me.
你们都说只要罗斯快乐  我就不该大嘴巴
You guys said I only had to keep my mouth shut as long as Ross was happy, right?
可是  他刚说他也不开心
Well, he just told me that he's not entirely happy.
这是怎么回事
What's going on?
我们都讨厌艾蜜莉
We all hate Emily.
才怪  不  罗斯  我们不讨厌艾蜜莉
No. No, Ross, we do not hate Emily.
我们只是认为你为了讨她开心  牺牲太多
We just think that you're having to sacrifice a whole lot to make her happy.
对
Yeah.
大家都认为她有点不可理喻
We just think that maybe she's being a little unreasonable.
对  就是不可理喻
Yes, yes, unreasonable.
不可理喻
Unreasonable?
要是以后你们谁结婚  大伙也有这种反应呢
How about we have this conversation when one of you guys gets married?
你们根本不知道如何维持婚姻
You have no idea what it takes to make a marriage work.
婚姻就是互相妥协  永远都会开心吗  不会
It's about compromise. Do you always like it? No.
但是你愿意吗   愿意
Do you do it? Yes.
因为婚姻不是只有欢乐  只有梦幻  只管上咖啡馆
Because it's not all laughing, happy, candy in the sky,drinking coffee at Central Perk all the time
婚姻是真实生活
It's real life, okay?
婚姻只适合成年人
It's what grownups do.
他说得有道理
I think he's right.
你们太常泡咖啡馆了
You guys hang out at the coffeehouse way too much.
我对罗斯很抱歉
God, I feel so guilty about Ross.
我知道
I know.
我觉得似乎都怪我
I kind of feel like it's my fault.
似乎
Kind of?
要不是你大嘴巴  也不会有这种下场
If you just kept this to yourself, none of this would have happened.
我最近知道的秘密太多  总有说溜嘴的时候
Well, I'm keeping so many things to myself these days,something was bound to slip out.
其实你很勇敢
Well, I think it's very brave what you said.
我坐不住了  我得去走走
I can't sit here anymore. I have to walk places.
菲比  你怎么还穿那件外套   你不是关心动物吗
Pheebs, what are you doing with the coat? How about the whole animal rights thing?
我最近读了一些书  告诉你们
Well, ahem, I've been reading up, and for your information...
貂不是好动物
...minks are not very nice.
好  我承认  我喜欢这件外套
Okay, I admit it. I love this coat, okay?
这是裹在我身上最棒的东西  菲尔亨利都不够好
It's the best thing I've ever had wrapped around me, including Phil Huntley.
你还记得菲尔吗   他帅呆了
Remember Phil Huntley? He was fine.
嗨
Hi.
原来你比较喜欢短发
So you like the short hair better?
什么
What?
雪人  你是丹尼
Yeti? Uh, Danny?
我得剪头发  因为杀虫剂的味道太浓
I had to cut my hair to get rid of the,fogger smell.
抱歉  我绝对不会再乱喷了
Listen, I'm so sorry. I would have never fogged you...
要不是你的样子实在太像
...you know, if you hadn't looked so... You know, um...
当然
Absolutely.
有些人只会以貌取人
Some people are just into appearances.
什么   没关系  无所谓
What? That's cool. That's cool.
什么  等等  什么无所谓  你根本不认识我
What...? Hey, whoa, no, no, no, that is not cool.You don't even know me.
你提着一堆购物袋  还拿着百货公司目录
Come on. You got the shopping bags and the Saks catalogue.
你以为这样就能看透我
So from that, you think you've got me all figured out?
不可能
Well, you don't.
搞不好我的袋子里装满  要给贫困儿童的玩具
You know, I could have toys for underprivileged kids in here.
是吗
Do you?
如果他们喜欢拿紧身裤当玩具
Well, you know, if kids like to play with capri pants.
随便
Okay.
不准你再说这个字   讨厌你老这么说
And stop saying that. I hate that.
随便
Okay.
好  我不该光看你外表
Fine! I judged you.
当时我只能靠第一印象  可是你也一样
I made a snap judgement. But you did it too!
而且你更糟糕
and you're worse...
因为你只相信第一印象
...because you are sticking to your stupid snap judgment.
甚至不肯反省自己对不对  你有什么资格说别人
You can't even open up your mind for a second to see that you might be wrong.What does that say about you?
对面那家披萨店好吃吗
That pizza place across the street any good?
什么  我饿了  要不要去吃彼萨
What? I'm hungry. You wanna get some pizza?
你还想骂人也可以继续吼
You can keep yelling if there's more.
随便
Okay.
随便  不准你再说这个字  讨厌你老这么说
Okay. Stop saying that. I hate that.
罗斯
Uh, Ross?
你还在生我们的气吗  对
Are you still mad at us? Yup.
很好  因为我们写了一首 "很抱歉" 的歌
Oh, good, because we have an "I'm Sorry" song. Ha, ha.
告诉你们  我现在心情不好
You know what? I'm really not in the mood.
罗斯  我很难过
Look, Ross.I feel really bad.
你生活发生巨大改变  而我却在乱讲话
I mean, you're going through all this stuff,and I just acted like a jerk.
对  我们都很对不起
Yeah, we are so sorry.
你们说出歌词了
You're stepping on the song.
我们实在太离谱了  其实  我们都站在你这边
Look, we were way out of line, all right? We totally support you.
无论你做出什么决定  我们都赞成
Whatever you decide, whatever you do.
歌词都被你们说完了  我还唱什么
Okay, now you're just taking lines right out of the song.
搬家已经够难过了
Look, this is hard enough, okay?
现在  真的很需要你们
I really need you guys right now.
没错  所以我们才要
Yes, exactly. And that's why...
你今晚过来  我帮你煮几道你爱吃的菜
Why don't you come over tonight, and I'll make you your favorite dinner? Come on.
好
Okay.
谢谢你们
Thanks, you guys.
菲比  你身上这件是貂皮吗
Pheebs, are you wearing fur?
别再大惊小怪了  这又不是用导盲犬的皮做的
Okay, let's get some perspective, people.It's not like I'm wearing a seeing-eye dog coat.
罗斯  我知道  我为什么突然爆发了
You know, Ross, I, uh, think I kind of understand why I lost it today.
是吗
You do, huh?
你知道我是个演员
Yeah, you see, um...I'm an actor, right?
所以我的情绪比较丰富  你了解吗
So I gotta keep my emotions right at the surface, you know?
我要同时面临多种情绪  你懂吗
I got a lot of balls in the air, you know what I mean?
我这种人的生活实在不容易  必须到处流浪   孤孤单单
It's tough. Guys like me, you know, you wander around, you're alone.
你胡说什么啊
What are you talking about?
我也不晓得
I'm not sure.
嗨  回来了  你刚上哪去了
Hi. Hey, look at you. Where have you been?
我去吃彼萨   跟丹尼去
Oh, I went to have pizza. With Danny.
怎么可能
How did that happen?
那个雪人口才真好
That yeti is one smooth talker.
希望你还吃得下  因为晚餐快好了
I hope you're not too full, because dinner's almost ready.
我回房间去就好了
Yeah, you know, I think I'm probably just gonna hang out in my room.
不  为什么
Oh, no. Why?
拜托你们
Come on, you guys.
要是艾蜜莉知道  我跟你们一起吃饭
Listen, if Emily knew I was here having dinner with you,
她一定会抓狂  你们也很清楚
she would flip out, and you know it.
没关系  我无所谓
It's okay. I really... I don't mind.
等等  请你留下来
Wait, wait, wait. You know what? Just stay.
拜托
Please.
我希望你留下来
It would really mean a lot for me if you stay.
罗斯  拜托你  跟我们一起吃饭
Ross, I just...Rachel, please, just have dinner with us.
好好好  乔伊  别激动  对不起  抱歉
Okay, Joey, it's okay. Settle down.All right. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
瑞秋  因为我是演员
You see, Rach, I'm an actor.
看  那个光屁股的丑八怪  又出现了
Hey. Hey, look. Ugly naked guy's back.
我好久没看到他了
We haven't seen him in so long.
天啊  我真想念这个死胖子
Oh, God. I really missed that fat bastard.
这可真诡异
Wow. This is so weird.
我刚想到这可能是  大家最后一次一起鬼混
I just realized this may be the last time we're all hanging out together.
他似乎也知道
It's almost as if he knew.
我来接
I'll get it.
喂
Hello?
嗨  艾蜜莉
Hi, Emily.
他在这里  你等等
Yeah, uh, you tracked him down. Hold on one second.
嘿
Hey.
对  我们正在吃饭
Yeah, yeah, we're, uh, just having dinner.
好  你等等  她跟大家打招呼
Uh, yeah, sure, hold on.She wants to say hi.
你等等
Hold on.
嗨  艾蜜莉
Hi, Emily.
嗨  大家好
Hello, everyone.
你们有谁在啊
So who am I saying hello to?
我不知道这里有谁  不过瑞秋肯定不在
Well, uh, I don't know about who's here,but I can tell you for damn sure who's not here, and that's Rachel.
最好是这样
Well, I should hope not.
罗斯应该很清楚了
Ross knows better than that by now.
其实瑞秋也在
You know what? Uh, Rachel is here.
她也在
She's there?
对  她在那边
Oh, yeah, there she is.
她在这里
Yeah. Yeah, she's here.
罗斯  切掉扩音
Ross, take me off speakerphone.
嗨  你怎么可以这样
Hi. How could you do this to me?
我以为我已经把瑞秋的事  说得够清楚了
I thought I'd made my feelings about Rachel perfectly clear.
艾蜜莉  我只是跟朋友吃饭
Look, Emily, I'm just having dinner with my friends, okay?
你就是喜欢跟她黏在一起
You obviously can't keep away from her.
你太夸张了
That's ridiculous.
我愿意为你搬家
Look, I'm moving for you.
愿意为你不见朋友
I'm cutting friends out of my life for you.
求求你  快搭飞机来纽约
Please, just get on the plane and come to New York, okay?
你就知道我只想跟你在一起
You'll see you're the only person I want to be with.
如果我在那边  就不会这么紧张了
I'll feel better when I'm there
也可以随时知道你在哪里
and I can know where you are all the time.
你不可能永远掌握我的行踪
Well, you can't know where I am all the time.
如果你不信任我  这个婚姻永远有问题
Look, this marriage is never gonna work if you don't trust me.
你说得对
You're right.
你能相信我吗
So... can you trust me?
不能
No.
好像很顺利
I think it's going okay.
他好像在微笑
Looks like he's smiling.
你怎么知道  你只看得到他的背影
How can you tell? You can only see the back of his head.
当然看得出来
You can totally tell.
你们看
Here, look, watch me.
微笑  皱眉  微笑  皱眉
Smile. Frown. Smile. Frown.
微笑
Smile.
大概玩完了
Well, I guess that's it.
怎么了  怎么回事
Why? What happened?
我的婚姻完了  什么
My marriage is over.What?
亲爱的
Oh, sweetie.
看看你  全身发枓
Oh, look at you, you're shivering.
给你
Here.
罗斯  需要我们做什么吗
Ross, honey, is there anything we can do?
可以的话  帮我跟阿甘要回家具
Yeah.You can help me get my furniture back from Gunther.
别再折磨我了
Okay, stop tormenting me.
这是貂   貂很坏
This is mink, okay? They're mean,
而且貂讨厌松鼠
and they hate squirrels.
很多貂都想被做成貂皮
And, you know, most of these probably wanted to be coats.
好好好  我知道了
All right, fine. No, I get it.
拿去
Here.
给你
You take it.
高兴了吧  我快冷死了
Are you happy now? I'm cold.